





Summary

Jump to Section

25 years of experience in Software Engineering with expertise in Account Management, Product Engineering & Delivery, Account Growth, Software Architecture and Team Management. Since last 1 year playing the role of COO for the start-up company- Wrizto. Earlier, worked for companies like Ericsson, Wipro, Siemens Communications (Nokia), Aricent (Altran) across levels from Software Engineer to Director-Engineering.

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Experienced in end to end product development life cycle right from Planning, Requirement Analysis, Design & Implementation, Development, Testing, Monitoring & Control and Production deployment using DevOps tools and processes. Experienced in delivering projects in various methodologies including Waterfall, Iterative and Agile - Scrum & Kanban models.

Work Experience

- Wrizto as COO-IT Oct 2019 to Till Date
 - 1) Formulated roadmaps and involved in defining solutions which meets organization requirements with minimum development effort and optimum application performance. As a core team working with Indian State Governments, Truckers associations etc., for sales nitch
 - 2) DevOps implementation: Brought in complete DevOps CI/CD pipeline for all Wrizto products with Jira, Bitbucket and AWS Developer Tools like AWS Code Commit, AWS Code Build, AWS Code pipeline and AWS Deploy. This helped to improve team productivity, code quality, testing and faster deployment.
 - 3) Telemedicine (SamVita) kit: This is a suitcase-based telemedicine kit connected with multiple (20+) medical devices and android tablet, generates an EMR when the devices are measured for a patient. The devices are connected via Bluetooth and supported over inhouse built live video conference, to connect to expert doctors at a remote place with EMR shared over a cloud network.

The ecosystem includes a Java/J2EE server, web/android applications for expert doctors, uses mongoDB to handle thousands of record data within a cloud network.

4) Wrizto: Ageneric multi-dimensional web/android app, cloud based digital healthcare aggregator platform with major Insurance companies, Hospitals, Diagnostic centers and Pharmacies. Currently implementing analytics in this app to generate Health Score Card. Setting up a product roadmap, adding multiple partners and working for a seed capital. 5) Mta: A product development to implement an IoT solution to integrate with marathon athletes and Coaches in real time. Coaches with their app guides the athletes' app remotely in real time with details and graphs of Heart rate, Pace, Distance/Run, Time etc., Environment: BLE sensors, android apps for runners and coach, Java/J2EE, mongodb and MQTT Mosquitto protocol.

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld Director Engineering (Jun 2011 to July 2019) Senior Engineering Manager (Oct 2005 to Jun 2011)

- 1) Championed AWS cloud SaaS based Internet of Things (IoT)/Machine 2 Machine (M2M) business enterprise projects with Mcroservice & NoSQL architecture using opensource technology stacks in complete Agile Security DevOps
- 2) Executed Digital Transformation enterprise projects for Mcrosoft, AT&T, STMNetworks, SMART Tech etc.,
- 3) For multiple years have been through the evolution of Network Management System/OSS across wireless domains 2G/3G/LTE and well versed with corresponding standards like 3gpp, tmforum. Worked for OEMs like Ericsson, Lucent/Alcatel-Lucent, Siemens Communications and Nokia.

Experienced in building analytical solutions based on ETL frameworks to study the performance of wireless networks and in building self-optimized networks (SON) applications which operate on multiple KPIs and measurement records of the network.

Experience in end to end product development life cycle right from Planning, Requirements Analysis, Design & Implementation, Monitoring & Control, Development & Integration testing and Production deployment.

Executed projects in Waterfall, Iterative, Agile and Kanban models and DevOps with CI/CD deployed (tools used include Kubernetes, ELK, Prometheus, Jenkins, Docker, Nexus etc.,) on AWS and SAFe.

Well conversed with Java/J2EE technologies, C++ with exposure to multiple databases. Well conversed with Atlassion tools, bitbucket, IDEs, SONAR etc.,

Experience in setup of exclusive ODCs, executing projects from scratch (proposal to deployment), transition of projects, handling of maintenance and support projects simultaneously for various customers.

Siemens Communications Software as Manager - Department Head Apr 2004 to Oct 2005

As Department Head, responsible for System Testing of 75% of Siemens OSS solution for core network called Switch Commander.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Andhra University in 1993

PG: Executive General Management Program EGMP (Not Specified) from Indian Institute of Management, Bangalore (IIMB) in 2013

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
C, C++, Java, J2EE		
Spring Boot, Hibernate, JDBC, Webservice		
Log4j, Apache kafka, Microservices		
Angular 2, MEAN Stack, JavaScript		
CORBA, VisBroker		
Tomcat		
Eclipse, IntelliJ, Maven, Git,SVN		
Rational ClearCase, ClearQuest, Jenkins		
Jira, UML, MS Visio, Ansible, AWS		
Sybase, MySql, MySQL, MongoDB		
SNMP, SSH, FTP, TL1,CMP		
NBAP, TR069, NetConf		
Waterfall, Agile, DevOps, Kaanban		
EMS/NMS, TMforum, 3GPP, GSMA		
GSMUMTS/WCDM4/LTE		
MicroServices	2019	2 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
devops	2019	2 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
CI	2019	2 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
CD	2019	2 Year(s) 5 Month(s)

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak	

English	Expert	✓	✓	✓	
Telugu	Expert	✓	✓	✓	
Hindi	Expert	✓	✓	✓	
Kannada	Proficient	✓		✓	

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: **General**Physically Challenged: **No**

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.